# **Ervan Muhammad Adrian**

#### Front-End Web Developer

Skilled Front-End Developer with 3 years of experience with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React/Next JS in designing, developing, testing and maintaining web applications. Want to face more challenges and experience related to software application development.

082127740922 ervanmuhammada454@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/ervanmuhammadadrian/ https://ervanmuhammada.vercel.app/

## **Work Experience**

#### PT Len Industri (Persero)

Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

Front-End Web Developer Intern

- · Impelementing Agile Methodology with Scrum Framework
- · Impelementing Micro-Frontend architecture with Webpack Module
- Collaborate with UI/UX Designers and Back-End Developers in designing and integrating dynamic data in applications
- Design the appearance of the application interface and create features and optimize web application performance with React JS and Tailwindcss Framework
- · Writing clean, maintainable, and well-documented code that follows best practices and standards.

#### **Universitas Komputer Indonesia**

Jun 2022 - Jan 2024

Software Engineer - Lecturer Research Assistant

- · Responsible for conducting information system analysis for each application creation
- Designing the UI/UX appearance of the application
- · Testing and debugging web applications across different browsers and devices
- Collaborate with Backend Developers in integrating data in applications
- · Responsible for designing frontend architecture, managing and testing applications in the Frontend section

## **Project Experience**

#### Go-Turtles (Dinas Perikanan Dan Kelautan Jawa Barat)

Nov 2023 - Mei 2024

Frontend Developer

- · Carrying out research and gathering information to be able to map the entire picture and use the application
- · Design the appearance of the application in terms of color, layout, images, and others
- · Create system designs for each component, text and color for maintenance needs
- Create UX designs to help make the user experience easy, efficient and effective

#### C2 Maps System - PT Len Industri (Persero)

Feb 2023 - Jun 2023

Frontend Developer

- · Carrying out research and gathering information to be able to map the entire picture and use the application
- · Design the appearance of the application in terms of color, layout, images, and others
- · Create system designs for each component, text and color for maintenance needs
- · Create UX designs to help make the user experience easy, efficient and effective

#### Point Of Sales - Kojek Bandung

Aug 2023 - Apr 2024

Frontend Developer

- · Carrying out research and gathering information to be able to map the entire picture and use the application
- · Design the appearance of the application in terms of color, layout, images, and others
- · Create system designs for each component, text and color for maintenance needs
- · Create UX designs to help make the user experience easy, efficient and effective

### **Education Level**

#### **Universitas Komputer Indonesia**

2020 - Present

Information Systems Study Program, 3.83/4.00

- · Actively participates in research activities as a teaching assistant in application development as Software Engineer
- · Designing a web-based information system of new madrasah students at Madrasah Diniyah MDT As-Siroj

#### **Dicoding X Kampus Merdeka**

(Agustus - December 2022)

Studi Independen Bersertifikat

• Take an Online Course with SIB Dicoding x Kampus Merdeka batch 3 on the learning path become Front-End Web Developer Expert and React up to expert class

## **Organizational Experience**

HIMA SI UNIKOM (2020 - 2022)

Minbakom Division Staff

- · Assist division activities in creating, managing and implementing programs
- · Make plans for implementing the activity agenda

### Skills, Tools, Certificate and Achievements

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Version Control (Git/Github), Figma

Hard Skills: HTML5 & CSS3, JavaScript, Typrescript, Reactjs, Nextjs, Redux, Cypress/Jest, Webpack, CSS Preprocessor,

Tailwindcss, Bootstrap, Agile Methodology, Scrum Framework

Soft Skills: Effective Communication, Easy Adaptation, Problem Solver, Flexibility

Certificate: Junior Web Programmer - BNSP (2024)

Certificate: Menjadi Front-End Web Developer Expert at Dicoding

Certificate: Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Web dengan React at Dicoding

Achievements: Best Capstone Project at SIB Dicoding x Kampus Merdeka Batch 3 (2022)

Achievements: Best Graduated SIB Dicoding x Kampus Merdeka Batch 3 (2022)